(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-pro-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
迫るショッカー
Approaching Shocker,
地獄の軍団
Army of Hell.
我らを狙う 黒い影
Black shadow targeting us,
世界の平和を 守るため
To protect world peace.
ゴーゴー・レッツゴー
Go, go! Let's go!
輝くマシン
Shining Machine.
ライダー (ジャンプ！)
Rider (Jump!)
ライダー (キック！)
Rider (Kick!)
仮面ライダー 仮面ライダー
Kamen Rider, Kamen Rider.
ライダー ライダー
Rider, Rider.
ライダー (ジャンプ！)
Rider (Jump!)
ライダー (キック！)
Rider (Kick!)
仮面ライダー 仮面ライダー
Kamen Rider, Kamen Rider.
ライダー ライダー
Rider, Rider.
とう！
Toh!
たぁー！
Tah!
あっちぃー！
Hottt!
いや、火薬の量間違えて爆発させすぎちゃったよ。
No, I mistook the amount of gunpowder and blew it up too much.
もう、せっかくの眉毛が燃えちゃうよ。
Geez, my precious eyebrows are going to burn off.
あ、雪民さん！ありがとう！
Ah, Yukimin-san! Thank you!
お！みんな！今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Oh! Everyone! Thank you for coming today!
そうです。今日はラミィの誕生日です。
That's right. Today is Lamy's birthday.
そして、今年のラミィは一味違います。
And, this year's Lamy is a bit different.
今年も体力作りで力をつけてきたけど、
I've been building up my strength this year too, but...
みんな知ってる？何でラミィがあんなに頑張ってたか。
Do you all know why Lamy was working so hard like that?
実はね...
Actually...
ヒーローになるためなんだ！
It's to become a Hero!
何！？
What!?
でも、ヒーローって言っても色んな形があるじゃん？
But, even if you say 'Hero', there are many forms, right?
だから今日は、自分だけのヒーロー像を探す旅に出ようと思うの。
So today, I think I'll go on a journey to find my own image of a Hero.
なんだ！？...いぃっ！
What is this!? ...Eeek!
や... やめろ！
S-Stop it!
おりゃ！
Orya!
ふん！... くらえ！
Hmph! ...Take this!
雪民さん...
Yukimin-san...
雪民さん... ラミィを守ってくれたの？
Yukimin-san... Did you protect Lamy?
さっきもバイク片付けてくれたし...
You put away the bike earlier too...
雪民さんは本当に偉いなぁ。
Yukimin-san is truly admirable.
よしよしよしよし。
There, there, there, there.
あ、だいふくも居たの？
Ah, Daifuku was here too?
ちょっとまた敵が来ないか見張っといて。
Just keep watch to see if enemies come again for a bit.
今日はね、色んなゲストを呼んで、たくさんのヒーローを見ることが出来るから、楽しみだね。
Today, I've invited various guests to see many Heroes, so I'm looking forward to it.
それじゃあ雪花ラミィ、ヒーロー探しの旅に行ってきます！
Well then, Yukihana Lamy is off on a journey to find a Hero!
なんで... なんでまた雪民ばっかり...
Why... Why is it always just Yukimin again...
僕だって... 僕だって...
I also... I also...
誰だ？誰だ？誰だ？
Who is it? Who is it? Who is it?
誰だ 誰だ 誰だ
空のかなたに踊る影
A shadow dancing beyond the sky.
白い翼のガッチャマン
The white-winged Gatchaman.
命をかけて飛び出せば
If you fly out risking your life,
科学忍法 火の鳥だ
It's the Science Ninja Technique: Firebird!
飛べ 飛べ 飛べ ガッチャマン
Fly, fly, fly, Gatchaman!
行け 行け 行け ガッチャマン
Go, go, go, Gatchaman!
地球は一つ 地球は一つ
The Earth is one, the Earth is one.
おお ガッチャマン ガッチャマン
Oh, Gatchaman, Gatchaman.
誰だ 誰だ 誰だ
Who is it? Who is it? Who is it?
海の地獄に潜む影
A shadow lurking in the hell of the sea.
強い勇気のガッチャマン
Gatchaman of strong courage.
嵐をさいて 雲きれば
Tearing through storms and cutting through clouds,
科学忍法 火の鳥だ
It's the Science Ninja Technique: Firebird!
飛べ 飛べ 飛べ ガッチャマン
Fly, fly, fly, Gatchaman!
行け 行け 行け ガッチャマン
Go, go, go, Gatchaman!
地球は一つ 地球は一つ
The Earth is one, the Earth is one.
おお ガッチャマン ガッチャマン
Oh, Gatchaman, Gatchaman.
誰だ 誰だ 誰だ
Who is it? Who is it? Who is it?
ビルの谷間に潜む影
A shadow lurking in the valleys of buildings.
赤い血潮のガッチャマン
Gatchaman of red blood.
夕日を浴びて 駆け出せば
If you dash out bathed in the setting sun,
科学忍法 火の鳥だ
It's the Science Ninja Technique: Firebird!
飛べ 飛べ 飛べ ガッチャマン
Fly, fly, fly, Gatchaman!
行け 行け 行け ガッチャマン
Go, go, go, Gatchaman!
地球は一つ 地球は一つ
The Earth is one, the Earth is one.
おお ガッチャマン ガッチャマン
Oh, Gatchaman, Gatchaman.
ハッ ハッ
Hah! Hah!
Go! Go! Muscle!
リングに稲妻走り
Lightning races through the ring,
炎の戦士をてらす
Illuminating the warrior of fire.
飛び散れ キン肉ビーム
Scatter, Muscle Beam!
勝利に向かって
Heading towards victory.
私は
I am...
(ドジで)
(clumsy, and)
強い
strong...
(つもり)
(I intend to be)
キン肉マン
Kinnikuman
走る
Running...
(すべる)
(slipping)
見事に
Spectacularly...
(ころぶ)
(falling)
ああ 心に愛がなければ
Ah, if there is no love in your heart,
スーパーヒーローじゃないのさ
You are not a super hero.
キン肉マン Go Fight!
Kinnikuman Go Fight!
ハッ ハッ
Hah! Hah!
Go! Go! Muscle!
嵐の必殺技で
With a storm of finishing moves,
けちらす超人レスラー
Kick about the superhuman wrestlers.
マットに真っ赤な薔薇が
A bright red rose on the mat,
今夜も 咲くのさ
Blooms tonight as well.
私は
I am...
(ドジで)
(clumsy, and)
強い
strong...
(つもり)
(I intend to be)
キン肉マン
Kinnikuman
誰もが
Everyone is...
(誰も)
(no one)
待って
Waiting...
(いない)
(is not)
ああ 果てない夢を追いかけ
Ah, chasing an endless dream...
あぁ 果てない夢を追いかけ
スーパーヒーローになるのさ
I'll become a superhero!
キン肉マン
Kinnikuman!
Go Fight!
私はドジで 強い（つもり）
I'm clumsy but intend to be strong...
キン肉マン
Kinnikuman!
走る（すべる） 見事に（ころぶ）
Run, slip, magnificently fall!
ああ 心に愛がなければ
Ah, if there is no love in your heart,
スーパーヒーローじゃないのさ
You're not a superhero!
キン肉マン
Kinnikuman!
Go Fight!
微かな密かな確かなミライ
Faint, Secret, Certain Future
聞こえないように
So it can't be heard,
俯く身体を
Looking down, my body...
誰か包んで
Someone wrap around it,
壊れる前に
Before it breaks.
弾き出し 嘲笑い
Repelling, sneering,
瞳を撃つ
Striking the eyes.
闇への引き金
The trigger to darkness.
踏み込む強さより
Rather than the strength to step forward,
抗う痛みなら
If it's the pain of resisting...
誰より嘆かで
Without lamenting more than anyone,
食らう Conscience
Devour the Conscience.
引き千切られたプライドが
The torn-off pride,
心に巻くブリザード
A blizzard winding in the heart.
ねえ ここから出してよって
"Hey, let me out of here,"
叫んでいいの？
Is it okay to scream?
埋もれた声は低い空が
The buried voice, the low sky...
いつも救ってくれたね
...always saved me, didn't it?
砕かれた幻想の果て
At the end of the shattered illusion,
でもまだ終わらせない
But I won't let it end yet.
My heart will doubt
悲しみ宿った
Sorrow dwelt,
花びらに伝う
Running down the petals.
涙が堕ちた
Tears fell,
儚き結晶
Fleeting crystallization.
未来さえ試されて
Even the future is tested,
篩にかけて
Sifting through,
残った現実
The remaining reality.
寡黙に見つめ合う
Silently gazing at each other,
夕陽はこの鼓動
The sunset, this heartbeat...
生かしてくれるだろう
...will probably let me live.
纏う With the truth
Clad in 'With the truth'.
転んだ今日がまとわりつく
Today when I fell clings to me.
萎れた感情伏せて
Hiding withered emotions,
ねえ 早く気付いてよって
"Hey, realize it quickly,"
叫んでいいの？
Is it okay to scream?
傾いた視界に淀む
Stagnating in the tilting vision.
道は見分けられるか
Can the path be distinguished?
ゲームは始まったばかり
The game has just begun.
この世に潜む現在を
The present lurking in this world.
My heart will want
いらない痛みなんてないと
Saying there's no unnecessary pain,
素直な自分足して
Adding my honest self,
ねえ ここまで来たよって
"Hey, I made it this far,"
褒めてもいいの？
Is it okay to be praised?
埋もれた声は低い空が
The buried voice, the low sky...
いつも救ってくれたね
...always saved me, didn't it?
砕かれた幻想の果て
At the end of the shattered illusion,
でもまだ終わらせない
But I won't let it end yet.
My heart will believe
GO FIGHT! マジ! マジ! マジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Maji! Maji! Majiranger!
信じてフューチャー
Believe in the future.
OK! オーライ! 勇気をこの手に
OK! All right! Courage in these hands!
旅立て!
Set forth!
君が超えたいものは何?
What is it that you want to overcome?
大空? 逆風? 昨日の自分
The vast sky? A headwind? Yesterday's self?
立ち向かう時 揺れ動く
When you face it, your heart wavers...
その胸に湧き出すパワー
But power wells up in that chest!
グリーン・グランド
Green Ground!
ピンク・ストーム
Pink Storm!
ブルー・スプラッシュ
Blue Splash!
イエロー・サンダー
Yellow Thunder!
レッド・ファイヤー
Red Fire!
冒険の始まりさ
It's the start of an adventure!
GO FIGHT! マジ! マジ! マジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Maji! Maji! Majiranger!
限界チャレンジャー
Limit Challenger!
勇気という名の魔法を持ってる
We possess the magic named courage!
GO FIGHT! マジ! マジ! マジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Maji! Maji! Majiranger!
夢見てフューチャー
Dream of the future.
OK! オーライ! 明日をこの手に
OK! All right! Tomorrow in these hands!
魔法戦隊マジレンジャー
Mahou Sentai Majiranger!
旅立て!
Set forth!
君が守りたいものは何?
What is it that you want to protect?
友情? プライド? 見えない絆
Friendship? Pride? Invisible bonds?
挫けそうな時 そばにいる
When you're about to lose heart, I'm by your side.
笑顔に初めて気がつく
Noticing your smile for the first time.
タウロス フェアリー
Taurus! Fairy!
マーメイド ガルーダ
Mermaid! Garuda!
フェニックス
Phoenix!
5つの手 重ねたら
If we overlap our five hands...
GO FIGHT! マジ! マジ! マジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Maji! Maji! Majiranger!
限界チャレンジャー
Limit Challenger!
勇気が勝利の道を示すから
Because courage shows the path to victory!
GO FIGHT! マジ! マジ! マジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Maji! Maji! Majiranger!
信じてフューチャー
Believe in the future.
OK! オーライ! この声よ届け
OK! All right! Let this voice reach you!
魔法戦隊マジレンジャー
Mahou Sentai Majiranger!
旅立て!
Set forth!
唸る大地 風は吹き抜け
The groaning earth, the wind blows through.
たゆたう水 走る雷
Swaying water, running lightning...
燃える炎
...burning flame!
GO FIGHT! マジ! マジ! マジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Maji! Maji! Majiranger!
限界チャレンジャー
Limit Challenger!
勇気という名の魔法を持ってる
We possess the magic named courage!
GO FIGHT! マジ! マジ! マジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Maji! Maji! Majiranger!
夢見てフューチャー
Dream of the future.
OK! オーライ! 明日をこの手に
OK! All right! Tomorrow in these hands!
魔法戦隊マジレンジャー
Mahou Sentai Majiranger!
GO FIGHT! マジ! マジ! マジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Maji! Maji! Majiranger!
信じてフューチャー
Believe in the future.
OK! オーライ! 勇気をこの手に
OK! All right! Courage in these hands!
魔法戦隊マジレンジャー
Mahou Sentai Majiranger!
旅立て!
Set forth!
第2話 仲間の力! 心が導くヒーローのカタチ!
Episode 2: The Power of Friends! The Form of a Hero Drawn by the Heart!
うーん…
Hmm...
たくさんのヒーローと出会えて力はついたけど
I've met so many heroes and gained power, but...
なんだかイマイチピンとこないんだよなぁ
Something just doesn't quite click for me.
かなた…
Kanata...
そうなの
That's the thing.
ヒーローってどうあるべきか分かんなくなっちゃって
I've lost sight of what a hero is supposed to be.
力があるだけじゃダメなんだ
Having power alone isn't enough.
大事なのはその力をどう使うかだよ
What's important is how you use that power.
かなた…
Kanata...
握力だけじゃ世界は変えられない
Grip strength alone can't change the world.
人々の心を守るのもヒーローの大事な大事な仕事なんだから
Protecting people's hearts is also a very, very important job for a hero.
そっか
I see.
力で守れないものもあるよね
There are things that power can't protect, aren't there?
そう！
Right!
だからヒーローにも強い心が必要なんだ
That's why a hero needs a strong heart too.
どんなにピンチになっても
No matter how much of a pinch you're in,
乗り越えるたびにどんどん強くなる心が！
a heart that gets stronger every time you overcome it!
さあ 僕と一緒に歌って
Now, sing with me,
強い心を掴み取ろう！
and let's grasp that strong heart!
うん！
Yeah!
プリキュア プリキュア
Precure, Precure
プリティでキュアキュア
Pretty and Cure Cure
ふたりは プリキュア〜！
We are Precure~!
一難去って また一難
One trouble goes, another one comes.
ぶっちゃけありえない！
To be honest, it's unbelievable!
制服着てても ふたりは
Even in our uniforms, we are
むちゃくちゃタフだし
insanely tough.
お互いピンチを
Each time we overcome
乗り越えるたびに
a pinch together,
強く 近く なるね
we get stronger and closer.
イェイ！
Yay!
Your best! My best! 生きてるんだから
Your best! My best! We're alive,
失敗なんて メじゃない！
so failure is nothing to us!
笑う門に 福来るでしょ！
Fortune comes to those who smile!
ネガティブだって ブッ飛ぶぅ〜！
Even negativity will get blown away!
生命の花 咲かせて！
Let the flower of life bloom!
思いっきり〜
With all your might~
もっとバリバリ！！
More vigorously!!
プリキュア プリキュア
Precure, Precure
プリティでキュアキュア
Pretty and Cure Cure
ふたりは プリキュア〜！
We are Precure~!
たまには放課後のほほんと
Sometimes after school, leisurely,
おしゃべり Very time!
Chatting Very time!
ウワサは恋する乙女の
Gossip is a maiden in love's
ビタミン剤だもん
vitamin supplement.
闇夜に浮かんだ
Floating in the dark night,
虹の架け橋
a bridge of rainbows.
ここに降りて
Descend here,
奇跡☆
miracle☆
イェイ！
Yay!
Your best! My best! 全力だから
Your best! My best! Because we give it our all,
友情 愛情 サイコー！
friendship and love are the best!
論より証拠の輝くえくぼ
Shining dimples are better proof than words,
必殺技で ハートキュン！
making hearts skip a beat with a special move!
瞳に ☆ほし映して
Reflect the stars in your eyes!
思いっきり〜
With all your might~
もっとキラキラ！！
More sparkling!!
プリキュア プリキュア
Precure, Precure
プリティでキュアキュア
Pretty and Cure Cure
ふたりは プリキュア〜！
We are Precure~!
プリキュア プリキュア
Precure, Precure
プリキュア Chu Chu
Precure Chu Chu
プリキュア Sha ba da ba da
Precure Sha ba da ba da
プリキュア プリキュア
Precure, Precure
プリキュア Chu Chu
Precure Chu Chu
プリキュア Sha ba da ba da
Precure Sha ba da ba da
Chu Chu wa!
明日は明日の風吹く
Tomorrow, tomorrow's wind will blow.
マジ意味分かんない
I seriously don't get the meaning.
今しか出来ない宿題
Homework we can only do now,
ガンバらなくっちゃ
we gotta do our best.
真逆のキャラでも
Even with opposite personalities,
あい通じてる
we understand each other.
夢を生きる
Living the dream,
チカラ☆
power☆
イェイ！
Yay!
Your best! My best! 生きてるんだから
Your best! My best! We're alive,
失敗なんて メじゃない！
so failure is nothing to us!
笑う門に 福来るでしょ！
Fortune comes to those who smile!
ネガティブだって ブッ飛ぶぅ〜！
Even negativity will get blown away!
生命の花 咲かせて！
Let the flower of life bloom!
思いっきり〜
With all your might~
もっとバリバリ！！
More vigorously!!
プリキュア プリキュア
Precure, Precure
プリティでキュアキュア
Pretty and Cure Cure
ふたりは
We are
プリキュア〜！
Precure~!
プリキュア
Precure
Chu wa!
ありがとう かなた
Thank you, Kanata.
なんとなくヒーローって何かを掴めた気がするよ
I feel like I've somewhat grasped what a hero is.
よかった
I'm glad.
きっとラミィなら素敵なヒーローになれるよ
I'm sure you can become a wonderful hero, Lamy.
その人を思いやる気持ちを忘れずにね
Don't forget that feeling of caring for others.
分かった
Got it.
ラミィなりのヒーロー像 考えてみるよ
I'll try to think of my own image of a hero.
ありがとう
Thank you.
それじゃ
Well then...
さらば〜！
Farewell~!
あ〜あ 行っちゃった
Ah, she's gone.
よし！
Alright!
この調子で次に行くぞ〜！
I'll keep this momentum and go to the next one!
今 忙しいの
I'm busy right now.
後で構ってあげるから
I'll play with you later.
あ…
Ah...
なんで…？
Why...?
なんで僕だけ見てくれないんだ！
Why won't you look only at me!
タラッタッタラッター タラッタッタラッター
Tarattattarattaa Tarattattarattaa
時に僕らは理想を語る非凡な才能 詩人で
Sometimes we are extraordinarily talented singers who speak of ideals,
またはキャピタリズムに屈する傀儡の卑しい子犬で
Or lowly puppies of puppets yielding to capitalism,
または語語が書かれたボードを掲げるデモの一員で
Or a member of a demonstration holding up a board of words,
いわば貴方にとっての疾しいホラ吹き野郎のオオカミ少年だ
In other words, I'm a guilty, lying 'boy who cried wolf' to you.
名声を
Fame,
体裁を
Appearance,
人生そのものを
Life itself,
潰し合おう
Let's crush them together!
恨んで 恨んで
Resent, resent,
恨んでもまた悔やんで
Resent and regret again,
描きたい存在に背中を刺される
Stabbed in the back by the existence I want to portray.
燃やして 燃やして
Burn it, burn it,
燃やしても手が震えて
Burn it, even if my hands shake,
嘘 白昼堂々 重ねて着込んだ
Brazenly piling up lies in broad daylight.
分かって 分かって
Understand, understand,
分かって僕の正義を
Understand my justice,
無能な怪物を距離で肥やした
Fattening an incompetent monster with distance.
妬んで 妬んで
Jealous, jealous,
妬んでいるまま選んだ
I chose to remain jealous.
その程度のちゃちな正解はいらない
I don't need that kind of cheap correct answer!
タラッタッタラッター タラッタッタラッター
Tarattattarattaa Tarattattarattaa
時に僕らは希望を託す聖人じみた詩人で
Sometimes we are saint-like singers who entrust hope,
またはマキャベリズムを隠した外見だけの置物で
Or ornaments that only look good on the outside, hiding Machiavellism,
または全てに噛み付くフリだけ得意なエキストラAで
Or an Extra A who is only good at pretending to bite at everything,
やはり貴方にとっての疾しいホラ吹き野郎のオオカミ少年だろう
After all, I must be a guilty, lying 'boy who cried wolf' to you.
現状の
Current status,
展望も
Prospects,
羨望も
Envy,
なにもかもが無価値なんだ
Everything is worthless.
存在を
Existence,
本能を
Instinct,
人生そのものを
Life itself,
潰し合おう
Let's crush them together!
恨んで 恨んで
Resent, resent,
恨んでもまた悔やんで
Resent and regret again,
描きたい存在に背中を刺される
Stabbed in the back by the existence I want to portray.
燃やして 燃やして
Burn it, burn it,
燃やしても手が震えて
Burn it, even if my hands shake,
嘘 白昼堂々 重ねて着込んだ
Brazenly piling up lies in broad daylight.
分かって 分かって
Understand, understand,
分かって僕の正義を
Understand my justice,
無能な怪物を距離で肥やした
Fattening an incompetent monster with distance.
妬んで 妬んで
Jealous, jealous,
妬んでいるまま選んだ
I chose to remain jealous.
その程度のちゃちな正解はいらない
I don't need that kind of cheap correct answer!
タラッタッタラッター タラッタッタラッター
Tarattattarattaa Tarattattarattaa
時に僕らは思想を諭す英雄的な詩人で
Sometimes we are heroic singers who preach ideology,
つまり貴方にとってのカリスマ気取った極悪非道なペテン師だ
In other words, to you, I'm a heinous swindler acting like a charismatic leader.
ねえ 生まれてから今日までの間
Hey, between the time we were born and today,
どれくらいのごはんで
with how much food,
わたし達はできてるかな
are we made of?
毎日ありがとう
Thanks for every day.
もし食卓からおいしいが消えてしまったら
If 'deliciousness' disappeared from the dining table,
ああ 迷わずに
Ah, without hesitation,
どこにいたって 何をしてたって
Wherever we are, whatever we're doing,
取り戻しにいこう
Let's go take it back.
あれは記念日の記憶
That is the memory of an anniversary.
何気ないあの味も
Even that casual taste,
忘れたりしない
I won't forget it.
ずっと一緒だよって
I have to tell you,
伝えなくちゃ
'We'll be together forever.'
かならず！
Definitely!
守りたい
I want to protect
この味は
this taste
キミと笑い合う
of the days I laugh with you.
毎日の
Every day,
いちばん傍で
it shines closest to me,
照らすあたたかい
the warm guidepost
道しるべなんだ
that guides me.
みんなと今 胸を熱くする
With everyone, now, the feelings that make our chests hot,
オモイ育んで
we nurture them.
これからも 大切に
From now on too, carefully,
刻もう キズナで
let's carve it, with bonds,
結ぶスペシャリティ
a specialty that connects us!
ホラ、キミに届く おいしいの中の たくさんのストーリー
Look, reaching you amidst the deliciousness are so many stories.
めぐりめぐって ここにあるって 奇跡みたいだよ
Going round and round, finding it right here, it's like a miracle.
約束 つなげたい
I want to connect our promises.
今がある キミと
The present is here, with you,
わけあいたい 未来へと
I want to share it into the future.
くじけそうな時も
Even when I feel like giving up,
負けないココロで立ち向かう
I'll face it with an unyielding heart.
みんなの しあわせな
Everyone's happy energy...
エナジーが作る
...creates these days...
この日々がうれしいよ
...that make me so happy.
デリシャスにあつまれ！
Gather for something delicious!
パーティは続いていくね
The party will go on.
世界中で 今も
All over the world, even now,
それぞれのストーリー
there are each of our stories.
ひとりずつが
Each one of us...
できることを
...is doing what they can...
がんばってるから
...and trying their best.
必ず 守りたい
I definitely want to protect it.
この味は キミと笑いあう毎日の
This flavor is of the days spent laughing with you.
いちばん傍で照らす
Shining closest by your side,
あたたかい道しるべなんだ
it's a warm guidepost.
みんなと 今ムネを
With everyone, right now...
アツくする想い
...I'll nurture these feelings...
はぐくんでこれからも
...that heat up my chest, from now on too.
大切に刻もう
Let's carve it into our memories.
キズナで結ぶスペシャリティ
A speciality tied by our bonds.
約束 つなげたい
I want to connect our promises.
今がある キミと
The present is here, with you,
わけあいたい 未来へと
I want to share it into the future.
くじけそうな時も
Even when I feel like giving up,
負けないココロで立ち向かう
I'll face it with an unyielding heart.
みんなの しあわせな
Everyone's happy energy...
エナジーが作る
...creates these days...
この日々がうれしいよ
...that make me so happy.
デリシャスにあつまれ！
Gather for something delicious!
パーティは続いていくね
The party will go on.
大切に刻もう
Let's carve it into our memories.
キズナで結ぶスペシャリティ
A speciality tied by our bonds.
第3話 闇を超えて！ねぽらぼビームで奇跡を起こせ！
Episode 3: Beyond the Darkness! Make a Miracle with the NePoLaBo Beam!
やっぱりねぽらぼだね！
NePoLaBo really is the best!
ねぽらぼ！はい！ねぽらぼ！
NePoLaBo! Yes! NePoLaBo!
だいふく、やっと来てくれた！
Daifuku, you finally came!
許さない…許さない…
I won't forgive you... I won't forgive you...
やみふく
Yamifuku
まさかあれは…ラミィにかまってもらえず
Don't tell me that is... He didn't get attention from Lamy,
負の感情が爆発して…
and his negative emotions exploded...
闇堕ちした、やみふく
He fell to darkness. Yamifuku.
そんな…だいふく、元に戻って！
No way... Daifuku, return to normal!
うるさい！
Shut up!
こうなったら、力ずくでも元に戻してあげる！
If it's come to this, I'll bring you back by force!
元に戻って！
Return to normal!
ど、どうだ？
H-How was that?
クソッ！
Damn it!
だいふく！
Daifuku!
畜生！
Dammit!
ラミィ！
Lamy!
かまって…
Pay attention to me...
ヤミィ
Yamii
わぁ、ラミィちゃんが闇堕ちさせられた！
Wah, Lamy-chan was forced into darkness!
これでラミィとずっと一緒だ
Now I'll be with Lamy forever.
ラミィが相手でも止めるしかないよ
We have to stop her, even if it's Lamy.
確かに、ラミィはタフだしね
True, Lamy is tough.
ちょっとぐらい叩いても平気でしょ
She'll be fine even if we rough her up a bit.
お、ちょうどいいところに雪民
Oh, Yukimin in just the right spot.
強化して
Reinforce it.
雪民さーん！いっけー！そりゃー！
Yukimin-saaan! Gooo! Hiyah!
雪民、ごめーん！
Yukimin, sooorry!
いけー！
Go!
かまって！
Pay attention to me!
まだだ…！
Not yet...!
Gaaaaah... Wa... ha... ha...
えー！？今度はラミィ、でっかくなっちゃったんだけど！
Eeeh?! Now Lamy's become huge!
仕方ない。あれを使おう。
It can't be helped. Let's use *that*.
お？あれ？そっか！よし！
Oh? That? Right! Okay!
みんな！力を貸して！
Everyone! Lend us your power!
ラミィのいいところをたくさん言って！
Shout out lots of Lamy's good points!
祝福のエールからパワーを溜めて、攻撃だ！
Gather power from the blessing yells and attack!
ラミィー！
Lamy!
よしよしよしよし、いい感じいい感じ！
Good, good, good, good! looking good!
よしじゃあこのまま観客席のみんなも、ラミィのいいところめっちゃ言ってって！
Alright, everyone in the audience, keep shouting Lamy's good points!
で、ウチらも言うよ。
And we'll say them too.
え？ウチらも言うの？
Eh? We have to say them too?
言うの！
We're saying them!
あの、ラミィのいいところ言ってこう。そしたら多分ラミィも元に戻るからね。
We'll say Lamy's good points. Then she'll probably turn back to normal.
あー確かに確かに。
Ah, true, true.
ねねから！
Starting with Nene!
はい！
Okay!
的へ行け！
Go to the mark!
よし！
Alright!
ラミィちゃんに！言いたいことがあるー！
I have something! To say! To Lamy-chan!
なーにー！？
Whaaaat?!
ねねのくだらないLINE、秒で返事してくれて...
Thanks for replying to Nene's silly messages in a second...
ありがとーー！
Thank yoooou!
え、優しい...
Eh, that's kind...
あら、いいじゃない。
Oh, isn't that nice.
これちょっと...
This is a bit...
来る？来る？
Is it coming? Coming?
おぉ！止まってる止まってる止まってる！
Oh! It's stopping, it's stopping, it's stopping!
じゃあ次！ポルカ行け！
Okay next! Go Polka!
よし！
Okay!
ラミィに！言いたいことが！ありまーす！
I have something! To say! To Lamy!
なーにー！？
Whaaaat?!
いつもさ！
You know how...
こんな頼りないウチらのこと、まとめてくれたり、ツッコんでくれたりしてくれて...
you always organize and play the straight man for us unreliable bunch...
本当に感謝してるんだ！
I'm really grateful for it!
だからラミィお願い、元の姿に戻って！
So Lamy, please, return to your original form!
どうだ！
How's that!
いいじゃない？
Isn't that good?
うぁああ！
Uwaaah!
効いた効いた！
It worked, it worked!
効いてる！
It's working!
よし次！
Okay next!
２周目２周目！
Round 2, round 2!
ラミィちゃんに！言いたいことがあるー！
I have something! To say! To Lamy-chan!
なーにー！？
Whaaaat?!
いつも！ししろんが！
Shishiron always...
小ボケをいっぱいすると全部にツッコんでくれて！
makes lots of silly jokes and you retort to all of them!
ありがとーー！
Thank yoooou!
こい！
Come on!
めっちゃこい！
Come on big!
いいじゃない？
Isn't that good?
ありがとーー！
Thank yoooou!
うぁああ！
Uwaaah!
効いてる効いてる！
It's working, it's working!
ねね行け！
Go Nene!
２個目２個目！
Second one, second one!
そう２周２周！
Right, round 2, round 2!
ラミィちゃんに！言いたいことがあるー！
I have something! To say! To Lamy-chan!
なーにー！？
Whaaaat?!
秒で返事してくれるけど！
You reply in a second but...
スタンプで秒で終わらそうとするの！
Trying to end it in a second with a stamp...
やめてねーー！
STOP IIIIIIT!
これ下がるんじゃね？
Won't this make it worse?
大丈夫か？
Is it okay?
あ、上がるはず！
Ah, it should go up!
あー！効いたー！
Ah! It worked!
終わらせていく！
We're gonna finish this!
Finish it!
いくぞ！
Let's go!
ラミィに！言いたいことが！あるー！
I have something! To say! To Lamy!
なーにー！？
Whaaaat?!
これをきっかけに！
Using this as a chance!
初期ラミィからやり直してみるのはどうでしょうか！？
How about trying to restart as 'Early Lamy'?!
バカお前！
You idiot!
やめろ！
Stop it!
やめろよ！
Stop it, I said!
あーー！
Aaaah!
効いた効いた！
It worked, it worked!
めっちゃ効いた！
It worked a ton!
やめろだって！
I said stop it!
分かったとる！
I get it, I'll take it!
ししろん！
Shishiron!
決めるぞ！
Let's finish this!
決めろ！
Finish it!
ラミィちゃんに！言いたいことがあるー！
I have something! To say! To Lamy-chan!
なーにー！？
Whaaaat?!
いつも！
Thank you...
ねぽらぼを！
for always...
大切にしてくれて！
cherishing NePoLaBo!
ありがとーー！
Thank yoooou!
うぉお！勝てる勝てる！
Whoa! We can win this!
これは...どうなるんだ！？
What... what's going to happen?!
え、どういうこと？
Eh, what do you mean?
やってくれるんじゃないでしょうね！？
You're not going to do *that*, are you?!
あ！落としたー！
Ah! She dropped it!
落としたー！
Dropped it!
イエー！
Yeaaah!
これは！
This is!
パワーが溜まったんじゃないか！？
Hasn't the power fully charged?!
よしよしよし！ラミィ！元に戻ってくれ！
Okay okay okay! Lamy! Please return to normal!
いっけーー！ねぽらぼ絆ビーーム！
Goooo! NePoLaBo Bond Beeeeam!
うぁああああ！
Waaaaaaah!
もう戻れーー！ラミィーー！
Turn back already! Lamyyyy!
ラミィーー！
Lamyyyy!
あ！
Ah!
ラミィ！
Lamy!
うぅ...ラミィは一体...
Ugh... What happened to Lamy...
元に戻った！
She's back to normal!
よかった！
Thank goodness!
だいふくの力で闇堕ちしてたんだよ。
You had fallen into darkness because of Daifuku's power.
いやでも正直、普段のラミィと全然変わらなかったから。
Well honestly, it wasn't any different from the usual Lamy though.
元に戻ってよかった。
Glad you're back.
あ！
Ah!
あれ？
Huh?
お？だいふく？
Oh? Daifuku?
だいふく...
Daifuku...
ごめんなさい、ちゃんと見てあげられなくて。
I'm sorry, for not watching over you properly.
ラミィ...
Lamy...
他人を思いやる気持ちが大事って教わったばっかりなのに...
I was just taught that caring for others is important...
上手くできなくて... ごめんね。
but I couldn't do it well... I'm sorry.
やっぱりラミィには、だいふくや雪民さんがいないとダメなの。
As I thought, Lamy is no good without Daifuku and the Yukimins.
ラミィ...
Lamy...
だいふく...
Daifuku...
ずっとずっと一緒だよ。
We'll be together forever.
まあ、いうことで、みんな、ラミィの生誕祭どうだったですか？
So, everyone, how was Lamy's birthday festival?
面白かった！
It was fun!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ラミィ誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday, Lamy!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
イェーイ！
Yay!
えーということでね、まだ終わりませんよ！
Well then, it's not over yet!
何？
What?
重大告知が、2つあります！
I have two major announcements!
2つ！？
Two!?
まずは、こちら！
First, this!
雪花ラミィ誕生日記念2025グッズ！
Yukihana Lamy Birthday Commemorative Goods 2025!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ということで、詳しく紹介していきたいと思います。
So, I'd like to introduce them in detail.
まずは、こちら！
First up is this!
みんなね、寄ってもらって。
Everyone, gather around.
はい、まずはこちら！アクリル…アクリルスタンド！
Yes, first up is this! Acrylic... Acrylic Stand!
テーマはですね、この後紹介いたします、
The theme is, as I'll introduce later,
フード付きタオルを身に着けたラミィの元気な姿となっております！
a cheerful Lamy wearing the hooded towel!
元気だね～
So cheerful~
みんな飾ってね！
Everyone, please display it!
続いては、こちら！ドン！
Next up is this! Bam!
おそろいトレーナー！
Matching Sweatshirt!
あーこれ欲しかったやつ！
Ah, that's the one I wanted!
可愛い！
Cute!
えーこれはですね、サイバー衣装のトレーナーとおそろいのデザインとなっております。
Um, this has a matching design with the cyber outfit's sweatshirt.
みんなラミィとおそろいにして着てね！
Everyone, please wear it and match with Lamy!
続いては、こちら！ドン！
Next is this! Bam!
ぬいぐるみキーホルダー ファンタジー私服衣装バージョンということで！
Plushie Keychain, Fantasy Casual Outfit Version!
ユニエリアのね、あの夏衣装を身にまとった
Wearing that summer outfit from Unielia,
え、ラミィのぬいぐるみキーホルダーとなっております。
uh, it's a Lamy plushie keychain.
可愛い～
Cute~
可愛いでしょう？
Isn't it cute?
これをね、身に着けていろんな所、ラミィ一緒にお出かけして下さい！
Please wear this and take Lamy out to all sorts of places!
そして、続いては、こちら！
And next up is this!
雪民フード付きタオルとなっております。
It's a Yukimin Hooded Towel.
すごいねー！
Amazing!
これね、あの雪民さんの顔がフードになっているタオルで。
This is a towel where the Yukimin face becomes the hood.
そこに居るけど会話してるわ。
He's right there but we're talking about him.
今後ね、イベントとかあった時に、
In the future, when there are events and such,
こういうのをね、身に着けてアピールしてくれると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you wore this to show your support.
いいねー！
Nice!
そして、フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And the Full Set Purchase Bonus is this!
雪花ラミィ箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入り
Yukihana Lamy foil-stamped reproduction signature & message included
えー描き下ろしポストカードとなっております。
uh, newly illustrated postcard!
うわー可愛い！
Wow, so cute!
可愛いでしょう？
Cute, right?
みんなもこれやって！イェーイ！
Everyone do this too! Yay!
ということで、以上、雪花ラミィ誕生日記念2025グッズでした！
So, that's all for the Yukihana Lamy Birthday Commemorative Goods 2025!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
そして、告知2つ目！
And, the second announcement!
なんじゃ？
What is it?
こちらは、新曲となっております！
This is a new song!
イェーイ！
Yay!
この配信の後21時から、フルアニメーションMVが公開されます！
After this stream, at 21:00, a full animation MV will be released!
あら！初めてでも？
Oh my! Is it your first?
そうなんです！初めてのフルアニメーションMVとなっております。
That's right! It's my first full animation MV.
すごい！
Amazing!
みんな見てね！
Everyone, watch it!
各種音楽サイトのリリースは、この後0時から配信されますので、
It will be released on various music sites starting at 0:00 after this,
よろしくお願いします。
so please check it out.
ということで、みんな今日はたくさんたくさんありがとう！
So, everyone, thank you so, so much for today!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとうね！
Thank you!
ということで、最後に新曲聴いていってください。
So, please listen to my new song at the end.
それでは、聴いてください。
Now then, please listen.
「無敵☆本気だサバイバー」！
'Muteki Honki da Survivor'!
ギリギリの綱渡り
Walking a tightrope on the edge
弱音はポケットの奥
Complaints are hidden deep in my pocket
しまい込んだら ただ進むだけ
Once tucked away, I just keep moving forward
こけたって即リスタート
Even if I trip, I restart immediately
そこからがスタートライン
That right there is the starting line
もう止まらないよ
I won't stop anymore
迷いなんてもうNo No
Hesitation is already a No No
不器用でも 前へ
Even if I'm clumsy, I move forward
超ハイテンションでいこうじゃん
Let's go with super high tension!
無敵☆本気だサバイバー
Invincible ☆ Serious Survivor
ゼロからでも何度だって
Even from zero, again and again,
メンタル最強モードです　見ててね
I'm in the strongest mental mode, just watch me!
限界歓迎チャレンジャー
A challenger who welcomes limits,
そう不安なんてさ　笑い飛ばそう
Yeah, let's laugh away any anxiety.
最前線　君次第
The front lines are up to you.
さあ行くよ Ready Go
Here we go, Ready Go!
ついてきてよねっ☆
Make sure to follow me, okay? ☆
トラブルさえ追い風
Even trouble becomes a tailwind,
ピンチもドキドキのスパイス
Even a pinch is just a spice for excitement.
ビシッと胸を張れ
Stand tall and proud!
遠回りも Go Go
Even detours are Go Go,
転んでも Try だ！
Even if you fall, give it a Try!
自分史上一番へ
To the best version of myself in history,
アクセル全開　ノンストップ！
Full throttle, non-stop!
無敵☆本気だサバイバー
Invincible ☆ Serious Survivor
ブレーキなんてお飾りでしょ？
Brakes are just for show, right?
ハート高鳴りモードです　感じて
My heart is in pounding mode, feel it!
完全燃焼フィニッシャー
A finisher who burns out completely,
そう誰より強く夢を叫ぼう
Yeah, shout your dreams louder than anyone.
最終章　君次第
The final chapter is up to you.
さあ行こう Ready Go
Come on, let's go, Ready Go!
置いてかないからっ☆
I won't leave you behind! ☆
最強☆最愛チームメイツ！
Strongest ☆ Dearest Teammates!
君の声がパワーソース
Your voices are my power source.
輝いて駆けてこう
Let's shine and run through,
未来へ Fly High
to the future, Fly High!
超ハイテンションでいこうじゃん！
Let's go with super high tension!
無敵☆本気だサバイバー
Invincible ☆ Serious Survivor
ゼロからでも何度だって
Even from zero, again and again,
メンタル最強モードです　見ててね
I'm in the strongest mental mode, just watch me!
限界歓迎チャレンジャー
A challenger who welcomes limits,
そう不安なんてさ　笑い飛ばそう
Yeah, let's laugh away any anxiety.
最前線　君次第
The front lines are up to you.
さあいくよ Ready Go
Here we go, Ready Go!
もっともっと
More and more!
ついてきてよねっ☆
Make sure to follow me, okay? ☆
みんな、今日のライブどうだった？
Everyone, how was today's live?
ラミィ、ヒーローになれたかな？
Did Lamy manage to become a hero?
新曲も、今までのラミィにはない、かっこいい曲だったでしょ？
And the new song was cool and unlike anything Lamy's done before, right?
みんなの感想、今日のハッシュタグをつけて、いっぱい聞かせてね！
Let me hear lots of your thoughts using today's hashtag!
そして！この配信のあと、21時から！
And! After this stream, starting at 9 PM!
新曲『無敵☆本気だサバイバー』のフルアニメーションMVが公開されます！
The full animation MV for the new song 'Muteki Honki da Survivor' will be released!
ついにやってきました、フルアニメーション！
The full animation is finally here!
今回のMVには、ラミィの大好きなものがたくさん詰まっています。
This MV is packed with lots of Lamy's favorite things.
このライブのあと、直接MVに飛ぶようになっているので、
After this live, you'll be taken directly to the MV,
みんなこのまま待っててね。
so everyone, please wait right here.
さて、まだもう少し時間があるから、
Well then, since we still have a little time,
MVをチラ見せしちゃいます！
I'll give you a sneak peek of the MV!
どうぞ！
Here you go!
無敵☆本気だサバイバー
Invincible ☆ Serious Survivor
ゼロからでも何度だって
Even from zero, again and again,
メンタル最強モードです　見ててね
I'm in the strongest mental mode, just watch me!
限界歓迎チャレンジャー
A challenger who welcomes limits,
そう不安なんてさ　笑い飛ばそう
Yeah, let's laugh away any anxiety.
最前線　君次第
The front lines are up to you.
さあ行くよ Ready Go
Here we go, Ready Go!
ついてきてよねっ☆
Make sure to follow me, okay? ☆
このあと ミュージックビデオ公開！
Music Video Premiere After This!
やみふく
Yamifuku
雪花ラミィ
Yukihana Lamy
生誕3Dヒーローショー ホロレンジャー
Birthday 3D Hero Show: Holo Ranger